Mouyad Abduljabar

1163 Golden Gate Blvd. | Mayfield Heights, Oh mouyad.gd@gmail.com | (216) 396-5206 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mouyad

SUMMARY:

Highly creative, innovative team player with over 15 years of experience with for-profit and non-profit organizations. Self-starter with proven record in business development, job placement and data analysis.

Successful nonprofit experience combines with prior for profit Human Resources role turning around organizations to achieve significant operation results/impact.

EMPLOYMENT:

Catholic Charities - **Employment Coordinator/ Business Developer** - Cleveland, Oh - 04/2013 - Present

- Proven records in developing business relationships that foster job placement.
- Maintain, review and analyze caseloads to ensure contract compliance are met.
- Facilitate clients through orientation and professional development training.
- Support Director and Program Director with data reports to assist with strategic plans.
- Develop business relationships with external non-profit organizations, community based organizations, colleges and businesses.
- Recruit and market externally for all programs that build center capacity.
- Experience working in an integrated system of services.
- Develop marketing tools to advertise center program services and events.

Neide Telecom - HR and Admin Manager - Overseas, KRG - 06/2011 - 6/2012

- Fostered a teamwork environment conducive to positive dialogue across the organization.
- Consulted with senior management to create HR policies and procedures; recruit employees; create group benefits databases; and develop orientation, training and incentive programs.
- Introduced company's first cloud-based human capital management (HCM) solution.

USAID/MSI - **Graphic & Web Designer Specialist** - Washington DC, Overseas Project – 11/2009 – 2/2011

- Designed, managed and developed the official USAID/Project web site in WP platform.
- Share Point content management on daily basis.

SKILLS:

• Self-directed, • Report writing • Excellent problem solver •Ability to work with and manage culturally and geographically diverse staff • Strong organizational and interpersonal skills • Strategic planning • Public speaking skills • Fluency in written and oral Arabic language.

Proficient in:

 Photoshop, CorelDraw, WordPress Platform, MS office, Constant Contact, Rezility App, LinkedIn, Variety of database programs, Web content, Web managing and developing, Branding, Marketing, Multimedia, Web and print design and ability to adapt new technology.

AWARDS:

- "Talent Vision" Award Catholic Charities 2015
- "Award of Excellence" Catholic Charities 2013
- "Design Award" USAID 2013

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Facilitated and uploaded all pertinent client case files for Employment and Training's third annual CARF review 2019.
- Assisted CARF surveyor with navigation of database, and all site manuals to meet compliance.
- Increased department revenue by \$11,700 within two months through coordination and facilitation of "Hardware Assembly Training" designed for immigrant and refugee population - Catholic Charities – 2013

EDUCATION and TRAINING:

- Al-Mustansiriya University Bachelor's degree in Business Management/Administration
- MENAITECH HR Certificates MenaPAY (Payroll System, HR System, Self Services System)
- Chemical Dependency Counseling Assistant (Ohio Chemical Dependency Professional Board) - License # CDCA. 169998
- American Red Cross Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR) # GYATVY
- Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Certificate of Achievement IS-00100.b Introduction to Incident Command System - ICS-100